Local 1199 Clippings and News Releases 5206-X
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Clippings and News Releases
1938-1970
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU)
RWDSU Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Employees Union
5206-X
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Records of the National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees document the evolution of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store drugstore local, representing pharmacists and drug clerks in New York City, into an international union of non-professional and professional workers in voluntary and non-profit health institutions, including hospitals, clinics and nursing homes, as well as drugstores.
6694282
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 17, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Between 1933 and 1957, 1199 functioned as a drugstore local with its membership growing to 5,000 workers employed in independent and chain drugstores throughout the New York metropolitan area. With its success in organizing workers in Montefiore Hospital in New York City, the union began a massive campaign to organize workers in voluntary and non-profit hospitals in the New York area, a large proportion of whom were black or Hispanic.
In 1973, the national union was established with locals in other states, including Pennsylvania, Maryland, South and North Carolina, Connecticut, New Jersey, and Massachusetts. The union combined organizing efforts with civil rights organizations, in an effort to achieve mutual political goals. Throughout the period of these records, the union was led by Leon Davis (president of Local 1199 and of the national union) whose administration guided the union's political and social activities.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5206: Local 1199 Records 5206-G: Local 1199 Guild Division Records 5206: Local 1199 Records 5206: Local 1199 Records 5206-S: Local 1199 Executive Secretary Moe Foner Records 5457: Mark Lillian Collection of Roosevelt Hospital (NYC) vs. Local 1199, 1962 Representational Dispute Documents 5510: Local 1199 Records 5520m: "Building a Union in the Hospitals: the Organization of Local 1199 at Montefoire Hospital, 1948-1958" Manuscript 5525: Local 1199 Additional Files 5651: Local 1199 Additional Records 5768: Sidney Cahn Collection of League of Voluntary Hospitals & Homes of New York vs. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union Arbitration Files 5680 OH: Local 1199 Oral History Project 5854: Local 1199 Additional Records 5871: Local 1199 Additional Records 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records 5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5933: Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union News files 5933 P: Local 1199 Photograph Files 5938: Local 1199 Leon Davis Additional Papers 5945: Local 1199 Additional Records 5948: Local 1199 (Rochester, N.Y.) Records 5984 AV: Local 1199 Additional Videos 5984 AV: Local 1199 Additional Videos 6016: Local 1199 National Benefit and Pension Fund Records 6062: Paul Friedman Collection of National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, Local 1199 Miscellany 6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files 6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets 6140: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project 6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings 6140 P: Local 1199 Moe Foner Photographs 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files 6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 6169 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 6209 AV: 1199SEIU Audio-Visual Materials 6209 PUBS: Local 1199 Publications 6281m: Local 1199 Biography files 6347: 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Records 6347 PUBS: 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Publications
Health facilities -- Labor unions -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Health facilities -- United States; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union; National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees. District 1199; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Employees Union (New York, N.Y.)
6694282
- News Clippings, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Press Releases, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- News Clippings and Press Releases, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Press Releases, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Press Releases, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Press Releases, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- News Clippings and Press Releases, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- News Clippings, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- News Clippings, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- News Clippings and Press Releases, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Press Releases, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Press Releases, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- News Clippings and Press Releases [folder 1 of 2], 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- News Clippings and Press Releases [folder 2 of 2], 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- News Clippings and Press Releases, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- News Clippings, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- News Clippings and Press Releases, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- News Clippings, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Union Voice Press Releases, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Strike - Public Relations - Letters to Press-Statements etc. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Extra Copies Press Releases (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Union Voice Press Release, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Press Releases, Letters, General (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Scope and Contents
  (other releases filed in subject folder)
- News Clippings and Press Releases (Box 3, Folder 6)
  No Date